Guide to the Paul P. Ewald papers, 1906-1990.
Ewald, Paul P. papers,
- "A Review of My Papers on Crystal Optics 1912 to 1968" by Ewald (Box 6, Folder 16)
- "Max von Laue 1879-1960" by Ewald (Box 6, Folder 17)
- New Year Letter, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Papers Sent to Academies, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Cambridge Talk - Introduction to Dynamical Theory, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Correspondence - Forman and Co.-Ewald in preparation of Myth of Myths, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 21-24)
- Atlanta Talk, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Cheer Song - ACA, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Corning Talk, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Talks, 1926, -56 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Talks, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Lecture Notes, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Lecture Notes, ca. 1929, 1943, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn (PIB) Dinner, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- [Sphere], 1959 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- "Physicists I Have Known", 1974 (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Amsterdam Talk, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 35)
- Parma - York Lectures (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Why Light Travels Slowly, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Sao Carlos Lectures, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Interview - part of Weiner's interview in N. Milford, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Bragg Obituary, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Limoges Talk, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Parma, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 42)
- Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 43-45)
- Reprints and Articles by Ewald and others (Box 6, Folder 46-65)
- Reprints - Renninger etal (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Dreschler, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Reprints, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Reprints - Palacios, 1943-1946 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- W. Pauli, 1919-1933 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Reprints (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
- Juretschke, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Debye (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
- Reprints (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
- Sakamoto, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Ultrasonics, 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Parratt, 1932-1936 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Papapetrou, 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Fues, 1938-1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Laue; Heis, 1931, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Hosemann, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Kohler; Niehrs; Moliere, 1933, 1954, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Hermann Article (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Historical - X-rays and Diffraction (Box 7, Folder 22-26)
- Papers (Box 7, Folder 27)
- The Physical Society, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Wiss. Correspondence; Kathleen Lonsdale, 1971-1973, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- ACA Transactions, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Ernest Mayer Dissertation, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- X-ray Crystallography Manual, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Technical Report, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Reprints (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Reviews and Article (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Reprints (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Kristalle und Rontgenstrahlen, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Elektromagnetische Schwingungen, 1913-1914 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Acta - P203 Zocher and Torok, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Acta - P153 Tommasi, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Acta - F10-F81, 1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Acta - A. F. Wells, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- Acta - Lists of Manuscripts, 1955-1959 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Acta - Summer Correspondence, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Acta - P59-70, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Acta - P48-58, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Acta - P31-47, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Acta - E343-602 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Acta - P346 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Acta - P332 [232?] Cowley, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Elektrodynamik S.S. 1921 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Truhe Munchner - Vorlesungln[?], 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Correspondence re Inauguration of Structure Reports; International Tables; Bragg, Bernal, Vergard, Laue, Abraham, 1930-1932 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Liversidge Lecture, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- [untitled] Photocopies (Box 8, Folder 20-24)
- Notebooks [German], 1906-1911 (Box 8)
- Correspondence [UPAP? CRU?], 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
- Mixed Projections, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Penn State Conference on Computers, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Graf mss., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Complex Symmetry, 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Wyckoff, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Sommerfeld's Optik, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Review - International Tables, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Hoppe, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Milwaukee Talk - Crystal Optical Surfaces, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Diamant [?], 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Guggenheim Foundation - support for 50 years, 1959-1963 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Symmetry in Fourier Space, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
- Paul Rosbaud, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Bienenstock F. Sp., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
- Belov 70; Correspondence on Publication of Paper with Bienenstock, 1961, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Bragg Lecture - Leeds (June), 1962 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- 50 yrs. Festschrift ms., Ch. 1-5, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Hans Bethe's Ithaca talk, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Creation of Journal of Applied Crystallography, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Bell Telephone Labs talk; silhouettes of Bozorth Family, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- New Milford Public Schools talk, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- James obit, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Eulogy for Isidor Fankuchen, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- RCA Court Action, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- ParthasarathyRamachandran, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- ACA Atlanta, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Debye obit, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Dynam Theory, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Ewaldite Model, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Mohonk, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Warren Award - D. P. recommends Gustav Borrmann, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Pittsburgh Defraction Conference, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Reorganizing Stuttgart University, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- "Translation of my thesis" correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Parma-York, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Donnay, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Syracuse Lecture, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Woolfson School - York, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Buffalo, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Diffracted Intensity and Electrostatic Energy of a Crystal, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Linus Pauling Institute, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 47)
- Goodman-Moodie, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Versuche, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Harker, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 50)
- Paul's [Ewald] birthday, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 51)
- Birman, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Cauchois Volume, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 53)
- Dynam Theory - Moodie, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 54)
- Hildebrandt, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Ewald on the beginning of IUC, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Halle, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 57)
- Dorothy Hodgkin, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Juretschke, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Rosbaud, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 60)
- Hahn, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Ewald obituary, commentary, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 62)
- Acta Ms., 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 63)
- Acta ms. Russell F311, 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Acta ms., 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 65)
- Acta ms. Flikema F253, 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 66)
- Acta ms. Pepinsky-Calderon F240, 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Acta ms. Buerger F197, 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 68)
- Acta ms., 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Acta ms. Newkirk and Smoluchowski F182, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Acta ms. Karle, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Acta ms. Pepinsky F181, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- P136 J. D. Haygood, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Fourier, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Fourier, 1936-1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Fourier, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Henry Lecture, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Thesis: "complete copy with my amendments" (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
- Brill, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Moodie, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- X-rays and Chrystals, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Reprints, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Book review, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Projects and Other Duplications, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Rose and Linda Ewald's school record books, 1917-1934 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Optik, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Hermvektoven, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Sydney lecture, 1961, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1911-1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Notes, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Glass negatives and photographs from gathering in Holzhausen, Ammersee, Germany at Paul Peter Erwald's mother's studio, 1925 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  Includes photo of Ott's carborundum structure with H. Mark, K. Herzfeld, L. Brillouin, R.W. James, A.D. Fokker, H. Ott, M. von Laue, C.G. Darwin, W.L. Bragg and I. Waller
  Also several photos of unidentified people
- Bibliography of Sommerfeld's Papers, and articles and clippings, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Einstein Archive, including copies of letters with Einstein and Sommerfeld (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Articles and clippings on C. Hermann, Laue death, Niggli, and others (Box 13, Folder 4)
- "The Full Costs of Ballistic Missile Defense", edited by Richard Kaufman (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Picture of Laue (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Lecture notes and notebooks, Gottingen, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Card catalog bibliography (Box 14)
  In wooden box, organized by subject, with lists in each box
- Card catalog bibliography (Box 15)
- Card catalog bibliography (Box 16)